Guide to the Residential College Task Force Records, 1985-1987
Duke University. University Archives
Residential College Task Force records 1985-1987
Duke University. University Archives
Duke University. Residential College Task Force.
1.5 linear feet Extent: 1000 Items
The Residential College Task Force was created by President H. Keith H. Brodie in 1985 for the purpose of looking at the establishment of a new living option. The collection contains minutes and other task force records, including correspondence, memoranda, financial records, brochures, application forms, floor plans, and other materials.
RL.01815
Language: Material in English
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the University Archives to use this collection.
For a period of twenty-five years from the origin of the material, permission in writing from the office of origin and the University Archivist is required for use. After twenty-five years, records that have been processed may be consulted with the permission of the University Archivist.
Provenance
The Residential College Task Force Records were received by the University Archives as a transfer in September 1996.
Historical Note
The Residential College Task Force was created by President H. Keith H. Brodie in 1985 for the purpose of looking at the establishment of a new living option. At the Task Force's first meeting, Brodie expressed his committment to the development of a residential college, noting that review of transfer students' reasons for leaving Duke indicated a desire for stable living arrangements which incorporate a community identity and a deeper intellectual life.
Collection Overview
The collection includes minutes and other records of the task force, including correspondence, memoranda, financial records, brochures and application forms, photographs, students' applications for membership in the Bassett-Brown College, floor plans, a draft and copies of "Duke's College Try", a memoir by professor Donald Fluke, memoranda concerning the faculty-in-residence program, information regarding the "Duke's Vision" pamphlet controversy of 1989, and other records. Topics covered include the Residential College Task Force, student housing, Round Table Dormitory, and Professor Donald J. Fluke.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Duke University -- Student housing; Fluke, D. J.
- Container List, 1985-1987, 1.5 Linear Feet (1 boxes)
  Administrative records are restricted for 25 years from their date of origin. Please contact research services for more information.
  - Chronicle, 1987 Jan. (Box 1)
  - Student membership, residential college
  - Bassett-Brown College (several folders)
  - DJ Fluke, 1986
  - Faculty-in-residence
  - Terms of appointment
  - Report
  - Items prepared for Chronicle
  - Misc. articles
  - Chronological, task force, ASDU, letters to/from Allen Bldg.
  - Monroe Hill College at UVA
  - Misc. notes
  - Residential colleges elsewhere
  - Shari Barkin
  - Residential life programming
  - Health and vegetarian eating
  - House Course
  - 2nd annual spaghetti supper
  - Brochure, "Doorway to a New Collegial Experience"
  - Application brochure
  - Residential college memoir
  - Loose material
  - Burrows, C and Laskey, C, "The Round Table," 1989
  - Manual for residential staff, 1986-1987
  - Minutes, articles and background
  - Fluke, Donald J., "Duke's College Try," 1987